# **Olin Kirkland**

Brühler Landstraße 2, 50997 Köln, Germany

me@olinkirk.land; +49 162 372 0898 / +49 162 479 1521

https://www.olinkirk.land

#### **SUMMARY**

I am an adaptable programmer and UI developer with a passion for making games, producing high quality OOP code, and creating user interfaces. My professional experience includes core front-end development for large scale applications, game development, and game design. In my free time, I work on personal game-related projects with an emphasis on procedural generation.

## **SKILLS**

- \* Expertise in Programming languages: ActionScript 3.0, Apache Flex, Haxe
- \* Familiarity in Programming languages: C++ (Unreal Engine), Javascript, C# (Unity)
- \* IDEs: IntelliJ IDEA, Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse, FlashDevelop, Flash Builder
- \* Adobe Suite: Adobe Animate, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop
- \* Version Control: Git
- \* Communication: Native speaker of English and German

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **George Mason University, Fairfax, VA, United States**

Completed coursework towards a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science September 2011 – June 2013

#### Oakton High School, Fairfax, VA, United States

Graduated with Advanced Placement September 2007 – June 2011

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

References to Adobe Air/Adobe Flash imply the programming language Actionscript 3.0

## **BRIGHT FUTURE, Cologne, NRW, Germany**

Game Developer, April 2020 - Present

- Work closely with other programmers and designers to develop and maintain a
  massively-multiplayer browser game that was ported from Adobe Flash (Actionscript 3.0) to
  JS/HTML5 (Haxe + OpenFl)
- \* Debug and refactored the game's codebase with an emphasis on improving performance
- \* Technologies: Adobe Flash, Haxe, OpenFl

## **DALLMEIER, Regensburg, BY, Germany**

Flex Developer, May 2018 - April 2020

- Worked closely with other programmers and designers to build intuitive user interfaces
- \* Developed various interactive modules for displaying and visualizing data
- \* Technologies: Adobe Air, Apache Flex, RESTful Web API

## **HOUSTON MUSEUM OF NATURAL SCIENCE, Houston, TX, United States**

Contract Interactive Developer (Freelance), September 2017 – May 2018

- \* Developed interactive touch screen applications and kiosks for deployment in the Houston Museum of Natural Science, one of the most popular museums in the United States
- \* Worked closely with curators to build content-rich exhibits to inform and entertain visitors
- Organized and led meetings with museum docents and volunteers
- \* Designed and collaborated to develop an interactive kiosk that uses LEAP Motion technology
- \* Technologies: Adobe Air/Flash, Apache Flex, C#, LEAP Motion

## PAUL BERNHARD EXHIBIT DESIGN AND CONSULTING, Houston, TX, United States

Interactive Developer, September 2015 – May 2018

- \* Developed interactive touch screen applications and kiosks for deployment in the Houston Museum of Natural Science
- \* Designed application concepts and layouts, and directed the organization and implementation of museum content for custom applications
- \* Wrote code to interface with custom hardware like the LEAP Motion and Arduinos
- \* Produced maps based on custom data sets using industry standard GIS tools
- Programmed visualizations for data from a wide variety of formats and sources including data from RESTful APIs related to the energy sector and extensive industry data sets
- \* Technologies: Adobe Air/Flash, Adobe Flex, C#, Unity, HTML, Javascript, Arduino

#### **ZENITH LEARNING, Houston, TX, United States**

Teacher (Once a week, Part time), January 2017 – June 2017

\* In addition to my full time job at Paul Bernhard Exhibit Design and Consulting, I worked part time at an after-school program at a magnet school in Houston

#### **RENAISSANCE CHILD, Arlington, VA, United States**

Camp Instructor, April 2015 – September 2015

- Created lesson plans and activities relating to subjects including mechanical engineering, stop-motion, programming, and robotics
- \* Supervised, instructed, and assisted students in a classroom setting

#### **ODESK.COM**

Interactive Media Developer and Graphic Designer (Freelance), June 2013 – April 2015

- \* Conferred with clients to discuss and determine layout design, and functionality of software
- Developed and implemented graphics and layouts for company applications
- \* Reviewed final layouts and suggested improvements as needed
- \* Maintained an organized archive of versions and products
- \* Technologies: Adobe Air/Flash

## **GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY, Fairfax, VA, United States**

Flash Developer (Part time), January 2012 - May 2013

- Developed interactive web applications to allow users to explore university floor plans and virtual tours
- \* Performed tests of web applications to be sure they produced the desired results
- \* Technologies: Adobe Flash